<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jose Dias</title><link href="http://jdiasn.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://jdiasn.github.io/feeds/professional.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://jdiasn.github.io/</id><updated>2016-04-30T20:29:00-03:00</updated><entry><title>AERONET on Brazil</title><link href="http://jdiasn.github.io/aeronet-brazil.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-04-30T20:29:00-03:00</updated><author><name>Jose Dias</name></author><id>tag:jdiasn.github.io,2016-04-30:aeronet-brazil.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;At the present time, there are nine AERONET station in operation across Brazil.
Five from these stations are placed in Amazon Region and the four others are
spread out over remaining territory. The AOT measured data may be classified
like level 1.5 and 2.0. This classification is associated with
algorithm applied to data processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" class="align-right" src="http://gauss.geofisica.ufrn.br/~ionosfera/zedias/aot/stationMap.png" style="width: 480.0px; height: 360.0px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In figure, the circles indicates where each station is placed. The yellow and green colors
are used to indicate the availability of data level 1.5 and 2.0, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Aerosol Data Validation on Brazil</title><link href="http://jdiasn.github.io/aot-validation.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-04-12T23:41:00-03:00</updated><author><name>Jose Dias</name></author><id>tag:jdiasn.github.io,2016-04-12:aot-validation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On Oct. 28, 2011 the Suomi National Polar-orbiting Partnership spacecraft was launched. It is
a result of mutual cooperation between NASA and NOAA. This spacecraft is composed by five sensors
to monitor Earth System. One of them is Visible Infrared Imaging Radiometer Suite (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://npp.gsfc.nasa.gov/viirs.html"&gt;VIIRS&lt;/a&gt;). One
possible utility is to monitor Aerosol Optical Thickness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Brazil, the National Institute For Space Research is data receiver of environmental satellite
data. In particular, my job is to evaluate performance of Aerosol Optical Thickness (AOT) on
the Brazil. The core of procedure is to compare AOT retrieved by VIIRS with AOT measured in
AERONET sites and with AOT retrieved by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://modis.gsfc.nasa.gov/about/"&gt;MODIS&lt;/a&gt; sensor. This project is under supervise of Dr.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lattes.cnpq.br/2921337850760630"&gt;Sievert&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" class="align-right" src="http://gauss.geofisica.ufrn.br/%7Eionosfera/zedias/aot/edrAnalyses/spatialAverage/diff201406.png" style="width: 480.0px; height: 360.0px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The figure above shows spatial difference for VIIRS and MODIS AOT data on June, 2014.
The result collection is hosted in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://gauss.geofisica.ufrn.br/~ionosfera/zedias/aot/"&gt;AOT Results&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>