<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jose Dias - Professional</title><link href="http://jdiasn.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://jdiasn.github.io/feeds/professional.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://jdiasn.github.io/</id><updated>2019-10-20T00:00:00-03:00</updated><entry><title>Radar Conference in Japan</title><link href="http://jdiasn.github.io/radar-conference-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-10-20T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2019-10-20T00:00:00-03:00</updated><author><name>Jose Dias</name></author><id>tag:jdiasn.github.io,2019-10-20:/radar-conference-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;From 16 to 20 of September of 2019, I attended the 39th International Conference on Radar Meteorology in Nara (Japan), and it is one of the largest conferences related to radar meteorology. This edition was the largest one with 158 talks and 329 posters which covered a large variety of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;From 16 to 20 of September of 2019, I attended the 39th International Conference on Radar Meteorology in Nara (Japan), and it is one of the largest conferences related to radar meteorology. This edition was the largest one with 158 talks and 329 posters which covered a large variety of topics such as new radar technology, data quality control, data processing, cloud microphysics, and of observation of extreme convective systems. During the conference, I also could interact with other radar scientists. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fphoto%2F%3Ffbid%3D2750772008292500%26set%3Da.139874309382296&amp;width=500&amp;show_text=false&amp;height=375&amp;appId" width="500" height="375" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowTransparency="true" allow="encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attended several interesting talks, but two of them were the most interesting for me. Dr Allessandro gave the first one, and during his presentation, he described the advantages of introducing G band radars (110 and 300 GH) for studying cloud microphysics. For example, the combination observations from  G and other bands (Ka-, W-) would be beneficial for retrieving microphysical properties profiles of cirrus, mid-level ice, and snow-precipitating clouds. The second one was presented by Dr Kenji Nakamura, where he showed a particular radar set-up for observing the melting layer. In this set-up, he used two Ka-band radars looking at the same part of the cloud. One radar at the top of the mountain was pointing downward, and another one at the bottom was pointing upward. Using this particular set-up, he was able to retrieve an attenuation profile trough the melting layer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had my talk during the first day of the conference in the morning. During my presentation, I showed the results of my study about the impact of large snowflakes in the rainfall. For this study, I combined observations from multifrequency Doppler radars (X-, Ka-, W-band). The results showed a correlation between the intensification of the snow/rainfall rate and the presence of large snowflakes. The results also suggest an increase in the thickness of the melting layer in the presence of large aggregates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am glad to have attended this conference for several reasons, but two are more significant for me. First, I had the opportunity to interact with other researchers/students from the same field and get/give feedbacs. A second reason is that, at the end of the conference, I received the prize for the second-best talk.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>PIRATA Project 2013</title><link href="http://jdiasn.github.io/pirata-project.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-03T15:11:00-03:00</published><updated>2016-07-03T15:11:00-03:00</updated><author><name>Jose Dias</name></author><id>tag:jdiasn.github.io,2016-07-03:/pirata-project.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In 2013, I had opportunity to participate on the scientific team of a 
&lt;a href="http://www.pmel.noaa.gov/pirata/"&gt;PIRATA&lt;/a&gt;
cruise aboard R/V &lt;a href="http://www.marinetraffic.com/pt/ais/details/ships/shipid:738424/mmsi:576785000/imo:8835516/vessel:OCEAN_STALWART"&gt;OCEAN STALWART&lt;/a&gt;.
Our main activity was to maintain nine oceanic buoys from that project. 
Between each buoy, we measured atmospheric and oceanic variables. 
The instruments used for those measurements were: atmospheric balloon …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In 2013, I had opportunity to participate on the scientific team of a 
&lt;a href="http://www.pmel.noaa.gov/pirata/"&gt;PIRATA&lt;/a&gt;
cruise aboard R/V &lt;a href="http://www.marinetraffic.com/pt/ais/details/ships/shipid:738424/mmsi:576785000/imo:8835516/vessel:OCEAN_STALWART"&gt;OCEAN STALWART&lt;/a&gt;.
Our main activity was to maintain nine oceanic buoys from that project. 
Between each buoy, we measured atmospheric and oceanic variables. 
The instruments used for those measurements were: atmospheric balloon soundings, expendable current 
profilers (XCP), and UnderwayCTDs. I performed some of this measurements using these sensors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fphoto.php%3Ffbid%3D534701559899567%26set%3Da.492950997407957.98857.100000791839387%26type%3D3&amp;width=500&amp;show_text=false&amp;height=375&amp;appId" width="500" height="375" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowTransparency="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The picture above shows the moment in which I'm disassembling the buoy and the 
OCEAN STALWART Vessel (&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.492950997407957.98857.100000791839387&amp;amp;type=1&amp;amp;l=4a102ba78f"&gt;more pictures&lt;/a&gt;). The video below shows the measurement procedure with UnderwayCTD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;iframe width="500" height="375" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sdf0DavHwrs" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>AERONET in South America</title><link href="http://jdiasn.github.io/aeronet-brazil.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-30T20:29:00-03:00</published><updated>2016-04-30T20:29:00-03:00</updated><author><name>Jose Dias</name></author><id>tag:jdiasn.github.io,2016-04-30:/aeronet-brazil.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;At the present time there are nine AERONET station in operation across Brazil.
Five from these stations are placed in the Amazon Region and the four others are
spread out over the remaining territory. The AOT measured data may be classified
as level 1.5 and 2.0. This classification …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At the present time there are nine AERONET station in operation across Brazil.
Five from these stations are placed in the Amazon Region and the four others are
spread out over the remaining territory. The AOT measured data may be classified
as level 1.5 and 2.0. This classification is associated with the
algorithm applied during the data processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" class="align-right" src="../images/stationMap.png" style="width: 480.0px; height: 360.0px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the figure above, the circles indicates where each station is placed.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Aerosol Data Validation in Brazil</title><link href="http://jdiasn.github.io/aot-validation.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-12T23:41:00-03:00</published><updated>2016-04-12T23:41:00-03:00</updated><author><name>Jose Dias</name></author><id>tag:jdiasn.github.io,2016-04-12:/aot-validation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In Oct. 28, 2011 the Suomi National Polar-orbiting Partnership spacecraft was launched.
It is a result of a collaboration between NASA and NOAA.
This spacecraft is composed by five sensors designed to monitor the Earth System.
One of them is the Visible Infrared Imaging Radiometer Suite (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://npp.gsfc.nasa.gov/viirs.html"&gt;VIIRS&lt;/a&gt;).
One possible application …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In Oct. 28, 2011 the Suomi National Polar-orbiting Partnership spacecraft was launched.
It is a result of a collaboration between NASA and NOAA.
This spacecraft is composed by five sensors designed to monitor the Earth System.
One of them is the Visible Infrared Imaging Radiometer Suite (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://npp.gsfc.nasa.gov/viirs.html"&gt;VIIRS&lt;/a&gt;).
One possible application of such sensor is to monitor Aerosol Optical Thickness.
In Brazil, the National Institute For Space Research (INPE) is the data center for
environmental satellite data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, my job at INPE is to evaluate the performance of Aerosol Optical Thickness (AOT) in
Brazil. The core of this procedure is to compare AOT retrieved by VIIRS with AOT measured in the
AERONET sites and with the AOT retrieved by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://modis.gsfc.nasa.gov/about/"&gt;MODIS&lt;/a&gt; sensor. This project is under supervision of Dr.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lattes.cnpq.br/2921337850760630"&gt;Sievert&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" class="align-right" src="../images/diff201406.png" style="width: 480.0px; height: 360.0px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The figure above shows the spatial difference for VIIRS and MODIS AOT data for June, 2014.
The collection of results for this project is hosted in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://gauss.geofisica.ufrn.br/~ionosfera/zedias/aot/"&gt;AOT Results&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry></feed>